<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Andrew Hundt</title>
 <link href="http://ahundt.github.io/" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://ahundt.github.io"/>
 <updated>2022-10-07T13:55:04-07:00</updated>
 <id>http://ahundt.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Andrew Hundt</name>
   <email>ATHundt@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Annotation</title>
   <link href="http://ahundt.github.io/2017/09/21/annotation"/>
   <updated>2017-09-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://ahundt.github.io/2017/09/21/annotation</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are papers that describe how labeling and data annotation is done such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1405.0312&quot;&gt;mscoco paper&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://research.google.com/youtube8m/youtube8m-paper.pdf&quot;&gt;youtube8m paper&lt;/a&gt;, those are likely worth reading. There are also a number of code projects to help you set up mechanical turk for your labeling problem, I suggest searching via google and github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some steps I recall from my reading which help address label consistency:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Often they start with a test to make sure the users on turk have an understanding of what they are supposed to do.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run the same data twice to make sure users agree, with some metric of the difference if it is not a per image label (for example mscoco’s segmentation).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have users evaluate each other’s work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Periodically introduce examples you have labeled yourself to make sure the users label data in the same way that you would label data.
Remove users and that aren’t good enough according to your evaluation in 1-5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suggest saving your annotations in a format that is widely used and for which readers/writers already exist, such as the mscoco annotation format, or youtube 8m https://research.google.com/youtube8m/.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some example annotators:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;https://github.com/nightrome/cocostuff#annotation-tool&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;https://github.com/CSAILVision/LabelMeAnnotationTool&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Resume Advice</title>
   <link href="http://ahundt.github.io/2015/08/23/ResumeAdvice"/>
   <updated>2015-08-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://ahundt.github.io/2015/08/23/ResumeAdvice</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve had a couple of people ask me about how to write technical resumes particularly applicable to programmers. Therefore, here is a general guide I wrote for improving resumes, I hope it will be useful to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-hypothetical-employers-perspective&quot;&gt;A hypothetical employer’s perspective&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things I tried to do in my resume is try to include the skills I gained in addition to the things I did. Imagine yourself as a potential employer, you are working on your job and you have too much work to do, or somebody will be leaving in the near future. Therefore, you need to find a new person to help out. Essentially you are busy and have a stack of 100 resumes to skim, then you will read 10 interesting ones in more detail. Your goal is to find someone who will be able to get the job done well, and at some level help you make money. Thus, what you are really looking for is a concise resume that tells you this new person has done something interesting, and they have learned some of the skills they will need in their new job while doing that. It is also good if they show somewhere that they took initiative to solve a problem, are eager to learn, and will learn quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;putting-it-into-practice&quot;&gt;Putting it into practice&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My explanation of the employer perspective is all well and good but it may be difficult to put into practice for improving your resume, so here are a few general ideas you might be able to make use of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Only have an address on the bottom, the top is the most valuable space on your resume. I’ve never had a potential employer use my snail mail address until after I was hired.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add “United States Citizen” if applicable, some jobs require this so it is good to have.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When I first started working and my resume was short I put a summary of the best stuff for the specific position I was applying for on top to engage readers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure there is a clear flow of information from important and bold on the left to smaller lighter fonts with details on the right. This makes the resume super easy to skim so the reader can find the details they are looking for.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Explain what skills you learned from each thing you did in an “additional experience” or “projects” section
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Some example questions you may want to answer for each project:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;What was involved in creating the project?&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Did you devise the plan? Did you collaborate with others on it?&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Perhaps you took what you learned from the first version and revised it to be better, that would show a useful skill of recognizing where improvements can be made and implementing those improvements.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;What was the goal of the project? Did you gain any new knowledge or learn a useful skill?&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;What skills did you get from your extracurricular activities?&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;These don’t have to be long, for example in my resume the explanations of what I worked on and what I accomplished or learned are 2 lines each at the most.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you’ve personally earned funding for a project you should include that information, otherwise I suggest leaving it out.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I suggest using PDF format when possible when you actually send the resume out, it looks better. I think Word has a way to export to PDF.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I keep my resume to one page.&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If your resume is currently short that doesn’t matter for you right now, but after a few years I dropped the summary section because I had too much info I wanted to include.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;information-to-consider-for-programming-specific-resumes&quot;&gt;Information to consider for programming specific resumes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What data did your projects take in and what useful results did they produce? What skills did you learn doing it?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Any of the following would be useful examples or experience:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Debugging tools&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Used existing APIs or toolkits&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Collaborated with others&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Picked up an existing code base&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Passed off some of the code or tools to others when you finished&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Version control tools and experience&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Worked on some small fun side project&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One additional thing that might be worth adding is a noteworthy tool or technique you had to understand or use to analyze the outputs. Any statistics, data structures, or anything else in particular worth noting about the analysis?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;code-samples&quot;&gt;Code samples&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is worthwhile to take a small code sample or homework assignment that you wrote and make it perfect and heavily commented so that it is ready to send to employers. One intern we’ve had made a small C program that creates an array containing random ints then spawns 8 threads to count the number of times the value “3” appears. I think it was originally from some assignment but it demonstrated her skills and understanding well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To decide what to sue for a code sample I suggest either taking a script you wrote recently or an old homework assignment should be fine. Make sure it is relatively short, has a clear purpose interviewers can understand, is well commented, and works. If you have something great on github or another open source project and public repository, you may also refer to specific changes you made although this can be more complex than sending a code sample that is exclusively yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t send the sample with your resume, but occasionally potential employers will ask for one. If you have a website you can link to it from there. Also, if you are really happy with your sample you can mention it to interviewers in person or in an email and I bet many will be happy to take a look. As long as the sample shows your skills in a positive light it can only help you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;website&quot;&gt;Website&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people also set up a website or blog with more detail and perhaps some code people can easily download and look at or videos of something you made, but it isn’t required. It is also great if in emails outside the resume they show excitement about the type of job they are applying for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up a website definitely isn’t required but a lot of people do so, and it is nice to know how to do. I wouldn’t write one from scratch, if you google around there are some nice blog tools or other ways to set up a simple website without too much effort or nitty gritty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you explain the skills ideas and contributions you will be able to bring to an employer that will get you to the next step in the interview process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this is helpful, let me know if you have any questions, would like feedback on your resume, or if I can improve the advice I provide here!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Intro to V-REP</title>
   <link href="http://ahundt.github.io/2015/08/23/IntroToV-Rep"/>
   <updated>2015-08-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://ahundt.github.io/2015/08/23/IntroToV-Rep</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here is some basic information for getting started with the robot simulator &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coppeliarobotics.com/index.html&quot;&gt;V-REP&lt;/a&gt;. Since the organization of their documentation could use some improvement, I’ll go over some of the key links and other important information. It is also worth loading up some of their demo scenes, which you can see with &lt;code&gt;file&amp;gt;open scene...&lt;/code&gt; It should default to the folder with lots of examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;key-v-rep-links&quot;&gt;Key V-REP Links&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll give a few links to some important parts. Be sure to take note of the icons they have at the top of their page, because they are key to matching up between their interface and what button to actually push.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coppeliarobotics.com/helpFiles/en/userInterface.htm&quot;&gt;Interface overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coppeliarobotics.com/helpFiles/en/calculationModules.htm&quot;&gt;calculation properties dialog&lt;/a&gt; where their internal inverse kinematics configuration can be configured, for example.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coppeliarobotics.com/helpFiles/en/scriptProperties.htm&quot;&gt;script dialog&lt;/a&gt; is how you look at what scripting is built into a simulation&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coppeliarobotics.com/helpFiles/en/childScripts.htm&quot;&gt;child scripts&lt;/a&gt; are how to manipulate objects in lua, this is the easiest thing to use and can be added by &lt;code&gt;right clicking on an object &amp;gt; add &amp;gt; scripts &amp;gt; threaded child script&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coppeliarobotics.com/helpFiles/en/apiFunctions.htm&quot;&gt;Full API Function List&lt;/a&gt; is the most useful page of all once the basics are covered is the full API function list:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coppeliarobotics.com/helpFiles/en/childScripts.htm&quot;&gt;keys to V-REP is child scripts&lt;/a&gt;, which you can see the icon for it at the link. Those are the small lua scripts you can modify, plus you may need a one liner in there to activate the remote API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;interacting-with-objects-in-vrep-programmatically&quot;&gt;Interacting with objects in VREP Programmatically&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve used any old GUI systems, you’ll be familiar with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coppeliarobotics.com/helpFiles/en/accessingGeneralObjects.htm&quot;&gt;handle system VREP uses&lt;/a&gt;. Essentially, physical objects in the simulation can be represented as a string or an integer “handle” which is an index into an internal lookup table V-REP stores. You pass those handles to the VREP API functions to perform a scripted action like changing joint angles on an object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;remote-apis-matlab-python&quot;&gt;Remote APIs, MATLAB, Python&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is their &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coppeliarobotics.com/helpFiles/en/remoteApiOverview.htm&quot;&gt;page for the remote APIs&lt;/a&gt;. I haven’t tried the MATLAB API or any other remote/external API myself. It is also worth noting remote APIs have reduced performance and a reduced set of  functions when compared to the lua and C/C++ APIs that I use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the external APIs, if you know python that may also be worth considering over MATLAB because it has an equally complete set of scientific libraries and doesn’t depend on a license. For those using the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.universal-robots.com/products/ur5-robot/&quot;&gt;UR5&lt;/a&gt; robot, I believe the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jhu-cisst/cisst&quot;&gt;cisst&lt;/a&gt; UR5 library is accessible from python although I haven’t used it personally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;python--studywolf-blog&quot;&gt;Python + Studywolf blog&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While not related to V-REP directly, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://studywolf.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;study wolf blog&lt;/a&gt; has a series of FANTASTIC tutorials on &lt;a href=&quot;https://studywolf.wordpress.com/?s=robot+control&quot;&gt;kinematics and control in python&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/studywolf/blog&quot;&gt;with code&lt;/a&gt;. The information on that blog is useful for understanding some of the underlying robotics concepts utilized by V-REP. At the bottom of each page on the studywolf blog you can browse more of his articles specifically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;using-v-rep-and-matlab-to-simplify-coursework&quot;&gt;Using V-REP and matlab to simplify coursework&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One more interesting link I came across uses &lt;a href=&quot;http://teaching-robotics.org/trs2014/&quot;&gt;V-REP and matlab to simplify coursework&lt;/a&gt; called &lt;a href=&quot;http://ulgrobotics.github.io/trs/setup.html&quot;&gt;TRS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;lua-apis-and-matrices&quot;&gt;lua APIs and matrices&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case it is useful, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/davidm/lua-matrix&quot;&gt;luamatrix provides a set of pure lua matrix functions&lt;/a&gt;. I haven’t tried it but it did take some time to find so I figured I’d share that. Also, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forum.coppeliarobotics.com/viewtopic.php?f=9&amp;amp;t=3991&quot;&gt;How to integrate an external lua library&lt;/a&gt; can be found in the V-REP forums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;scene-hierarchy&quot;&gt;Scene Hierarchy&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coppeliarobotics.com/helpFiles/en/userInterface.htm&quot;&gt;Scene Hierarchy&lt;/a&gt; is the list of objects on the left-hand side of V-REP with things that are already in your simulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes there will be a tab indentation of one object to the bottom right of the other, this is particularly obvious when you look at an arm and how all the indentations slant to the right from top to bottom. This Indentation means that the object is represented in the coordinate frame of the parent object, so if you for example rotate the first link of the arm all the child links are moved with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used this in combination with dummy objects for my system. Dummy objects are useful because they provide a physical frame that you can see in the simulation to attach your objects to and move everything relative to. For example with my bone which had an optical tracker fiducial attached, I put a dummy object a position where the fiducials control point is I made the bone a child that so then when I move the bone The optical tracker would detect that and set the position of the dummy the new detected position on the bone with corresponding we move in the simulation to it’s real time position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully that is a decent amount of starter info pointing to some of the key items!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>